JOY CHOU

Staff Engineer

Contact Information

Shanghai China (+86)18010526842 joy060102@gmail.com

Github:

https://github.com/jooyyy

Skills

- Golang
- Solidity
- Swift
- Java
- TypeScript
- MySQL

Languages

- Mandarin
- English

Self-motivated software engineer with over 8 years hand-on experience, of which more than 5 years in the field of Web3. I have rich project experience from 0 to 1 landing, covering public chain, decentralized wallet, explorer, NFT and DeFi.



Employment History

Staff Engineer Oct 2020 - Present

Validus DC Systems • Hong Kong

- Working as the ecological project leader, build the block explorer / decentralized wallet / SDKs / NFT platform for V Systems public chain.
- Lead cross-chain-based technical solutions to serve our DeFi products, explored the practice of OrderBook and AMM DeFi projects on Ethereum.
- Lead the mobile project for Hong Kong Gold and Silver Exchange, based on TSS multiple signature protocol and HOT / COLD separation scheme.

Vice President Of Engineering Oct 2017 - Jul 2020

Togreat Technology • Shenzhen

- Built and managed an 6-person team to develop a decentralized HD wallet for Bitcoin / Ethereum / EOS / TRON / Vsys.
- Integrated the built-in browser to support our own and third-party DApps to be used inside our wallet.
- Led and trained the R&D team to gain a deeper understanding of cuttingedge technologies in the Web3 field.
- Helped the company obtain more than 1.5M seed round investment.

Senior Software Engineer Aug 2014 - Jul 2017

Zhuozhuo Technology • Chengdu

- Led the development of X-VPN mobile client from 0-1, achieved more than 50M downloads.
- Responsible for the project architecture of the mobile projects, realized the componentization and modularization of the projects.
- Developed the SDK for cross platform client RPC and core function library, significantly reduced development costs.
- Helped the company obtain more than 8M investment through this product.



Education

Bachelor's Network Engineering Sep 2011 - Jul 2015

The *University of Electronic Science and Technology of China* • Chengdu Sichuan